We were excited by these results, but then Jim stood up, and what occurred was truly remarkable. All the natural biomechanics mediated by the central nervous system emerged via the synthetic limb as an involuntary, reflexive action. All the intricacies of foot placement during stair ascent -- (Applause) emerged before our eyes. Here's Jim descending steps, reaching with his bionic toe to the next stair tread, automatically exhibiting natural motions without him even trying to move his limb. Because Jim's central nervous system is receiving the proprioceptive signals, it knows exactly how to control the synthetic limb in a natural way. Now, Jim moves and behaves as if the synthetic limb is part of him. For example, one day in the lab, he accidentally stepped on a roll of electrical tape. Now, what do you do when something's stuck to your shoe? You don't reach down like this; it's way too awkward. Instead, you shake it off, and that's exactly what Jim did after being neurally connected to the limb for just a few hours. What was most interesting to me is what Jim was telling us he was experiencing. He said, "The robot became part of me." Jim Ewing: The morning after the first time I was attached to the robot, my daughter came downstairs and asked me how it felt to be a cyborg, and my answer was that I didn't feel like a cyborg. I felt like I had my leg, and it wasn't that I was attached to the robot so much as the robot was attached to me, and the robot became part of me. It became my leg pretty quickly. Hugh Herr: Thank you. (Applause) By connecting Jim's nervous system bidirectionally to his synthetic limb, neurological embodiment was achieved. I hypothesized that because Jim can think and move his synthetic limb, and because he can feel those movements within his nervous system, the prosthesis is no longer a separate tool, but an integral part of Jim, an integral part of his body. Because of this neurological embodiment, Jim doesn't feel like a cyborg. He feels like he just has his leg back, that he has his body back. Now I'm often asked when I'm going to be neurally linked to my synthetic limbs bidirectionally, when I'm going to become a cyborg. The truth is, I'm hesitant to become a cyborg. Before my legs were amputated, I was a terrible student. I got D's and often F's in school. Then, after my limbs were amputated, I suddenly became an MIT professor. (Laughter) (Applause) Now I'm worried that once I'm neurally connected to my limbs once again, my brain will remap back to its not-so-bright self. (Laughter) But you know what, that's OK, because at MIT, I already have tenure. (Applause) I believe the reach of NeuroEmbodied Design will extend far beyond limb replacement and will carry humanity into realms that fundamentally redefine human potential. In this 21st century, designers will extend the nervous system into powerfully strong exoskeletons that humans can control and feel with their minds. Muscles within the body can be reconfigured for the control of powerful motors, and to feel and sense exoskeletal movements, augmenting humans' strength, jumping height and running speed. In this 21st century, I believe humans will become superheroes. Humans may also extend their bodies into non-anthropomorphic structures, such as wings, controlling and feeling each wing movement within the nervous system. Leonardo da Vinci said, "When once you have tasted flight, you will forever walk the earth with your eyes turned skyward, for there you have been and there you will always long to return." During the twilight years of this century, I believe humans will be unrecognizable in morphology and dynamics from what we are today. Humanity will take flight and soar. Jim Ewing fell to earth and was badly broken, but his eyes turned skyward, where he always longed to return. After his accident, he not only dreamed to walk again, but also to return to his chosen sport of mountain climbing. At MIT, Team Cyborg built Jim a specialized limb for the vertical world, a brain-controlled leg with full position and movement sensations. Using this technology, Jim returned to the Cayman Islands, the site of his accident, rebuilt as a cyborg to climb skyward once again. (Crashing waves) (Applause) Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, Jim Ewing, the first cyborg rock climber. (Applause)
Nous étions excités par ces résultats, lorsque Jim se leva, et là, ce fut vraiment remarquable. Toute la biomécanique naturelle traitée par le système nerveux central apparut dans le membre synthétique comme un acte involontaire et automatique. Toutes les subtilités du placement de pied lors d'une montée de marches – (Applaudissements) apparurent devant nos yeux. Ici, la descente de Jim, ses doigts bioniques approchant la prochaine marche, faisant preuve de mouvements naturels automatiquement, sans efforts. Comme le système nerveux central de Jim reçoit les signaux proprioceptiques, il sait contrôler le membre synthétique de façon naturelle. Jim bouge et se comporte comme si le membre synthétique lui appartenait. Par exemple, un jour au labo, il marcha par erreur sur un rouleau de ruban adhésif. Que fait-on dans ce cas-là ? On ne se baisse pas comme ça ; c’est trop gênant. On le secoue. C’est exactement ce que fit Jim seulement quelques heures après avoir été connecté. Le plus intéressant pour moi, c'est quand Jim nous raconta son expérience. Il dit : « Le robot fait partie de moi. » Jim Ewing : Le lendemain de ma première connexion au robot, ma fille descendit et me demanda ce que ça fait d’être un cyborg. Ma réponse fut que je ne me sentais pas cyborg. J’avais l’impression d’avoir ma jambe et que je n’étais pas attaché au robot autant qu’il n’était attaché à moi et qu’il faisait partie de moi. C’est vite devenu ma jambe. Hugh Herr : Merci. (Applaudissements) En connectant le système nerveux de Jim, de façon bidirectionnelle, à son membre synthétique, on obtint l’incarnation neurologique. J’ai postulé que parce que Jim peut penser et bouger son membre synthétique, et parce qu’il ressent ces mouvements dans son propre système nerveux, la prothèse n’est plus un outil distinct, mais fait partie intégrante du corps de Jim. Grâce à l’incarnation neurologique, Jim ne se sent pas cyborg. Il sent simplement qu’il a retrouvé ses jambes, son corps. On me demande souvent quand je vais me faire relier à mes membres de manière bidirectionnelle, quand je vais devenir un cyborg. J’hésite à devenir un cyborg. Avant mon amputation, j’étais un élève nul. J’avais des notes terribles à l’école. Mais après mon amputation, je suis devenu professeur à MIT. (Rires) (Applaudissements) J’ai peur que si je reconnecte mes neurones à mes membres, mon cerveau va retrouver sa forme moins intelligente. (Rires) Mais bon, ça va, je suis déjà titularisé au MIT. (Applaudissements) Je crois que la portée du design NeuroIncarné s’étendra bien au-delà du remplacement de membres et entrainera l’humanité dans des contrées qui redéfiniront complètement le potentiel humain. Au 21e siècle, on prolongera le système nerveux dans de puissants exosquelettes que les humains pourront contrôler et sentir avec leur cerveau. Les muscles du corps pourront être reconfigurés pour contrôler des moteurs puissants et pour sentir les mouvements de l’exosquelette, ce qui augmentera notre force, l’amplitude de nos sauts et notre vitesse. Au 21e siècle, je crois que les humains deviendront des super-héros. On pourra aussi prolonger nos corps dans des structures non-anthropomorphes, comme des ailes, contrôlant et sentant chaque mouvement dans notre système nerveux. Léonard de Vinci a dit : « Quiconque aura goûté au vol marchera à jamais les yeux tournés vers le ciel, car là il a été, et là toujours il désirera ardemment retourner. » Au crépuscule de ce siècle, les humains seront méconnaissables, de par leur morphologie et leur mouvement. L’humanité va prendre son envol. Jim Ewing chuta, il fut brisé, mais ses yeux se tournèrent vers le ciel, là où il rêvait de retourner. Après son accident, il rêvait de marcher et de retrouver son sport favori : l’escalade. Au MIT, Team Cyborg a construit pour Jim un membre adapté au monde vertical, une jambe contrôlée par le cerveau, avec une gamme complète de sensations. Armé de cette technologie, Jim regagna les Îles Caïman, le site de son accident, rebâti en cyborg, pour grimper de nouveau vers le ciel. (Fracas de vagues) (Applaudissements) Merci. Mesdames et messieurs, Jim Ewing, le premier grimpeur cyborg. (Applaudissements)